for people who don’t understand the law Yes, it’s easier to
людям которые не понимают праве Да легче
hang noodles on their ears yes But I won’t
Лапшу вешать на уши да А мне не
be able to yes
получится
here Accept fines here fines there Yes
тут штрафы там штрафы
How are
Да Как у вас дела ЧМ из города
you doing?
откуда Да я знаю Вы в тот раз показывали
there are cars, property
отнимают там машины имущество
in the early days
заре
I didn’t show you this bill I didn’t
я вам не показывал этот законопроект Я
see this bill And you didn’t
не видел этот законопроект А вы не
see the bill I understood
видели законопроект понял
you were confused Well, I talked to you once on the
путали Ну с вами я общался как-то на
radio, even on what
радио даже на каком
radio Well, there was a coalition of bloggers A bunch
радио Ну там коалиция была блогеров Куча
of you started some kind of monologue there  It
у вас там какой-то монолог начался Это
probably wasn’t me, but look, I’ll say this, I
не я был наверное да но смотрите я скажу
haven’t read this bill, but I
так я этот законопроект не читал но я
saw it in the news. Yes, what do they propose to take away property from those
видел в новостях Да что предлагают у тех
who spread fake news about the army? news
кто распространяет фейки об армии
yes, yes,
забирать имущество новость да да много
there are many many stupid bills in any
много глупых законопроектов есть в любой
country, but the point is that  there is a first
стране но суть в том то что есть первое
reading, a second reading, a third reading, then the
чтение второе чтение третье чтение потом
deputies pass the law, then the
депутаты принимают закон потом Совет
Federation Council approves or disapproves of this
Федерации одобряет либо не одобряет этот
law, then
закон потом подписывает документ
the president signs the document, only then does
президент конкретно только тогда
it become law Why the hell did you
становится это законом Нахрена вы это
tell me all this Why the hell did you tell me all this
рассказали А нахрена вы мне это всё
Just one blogger
рассказали Просто мне один блогер
showed me I’m a man  with a legal
показывал Я человек с юридическим
education I know how the legislative
образованием Я знаю как законотворческий
process happens, I don’t know the Porus of
процесс происходит не знаю Порус
legislative reading, to which they
законотворческого чтение на что меня
immediately threw me off now, as if I’m sitting here, as
сразу скинули теперь как бы вот сижу как
if like this, look at the EU, if such
бы вот так вот смотрите ес если в первом
bills pass in the first reading, this is
чтении проходят такие законопроекты это
already some kind of right thing, they
уже какой-то пра
missed this. Why  no, no matter what, you wouldn’t have
пропустили А почему нет как сри у вас бы
missed it in the first For example, a law
в первом ни пропустили бы Например закон
on shooting everyone who uses, for example,
о расстреле всех кто пользуется например
an iPhone No, of course And Instagram, you see,
Айфоном Нет конечно И инстагра да видишь
no one would have said Why not And
никто бы не сказал А почему бы и нет А
why here Yes, for fakes, the army was proposed to
почему тут Да за фейки армии предложили
deprive the army of property and voted in the
лишать имущество и проголосовали в
first reading  no one said that this does not
первом чтении никто не сказал что это не
comply with the Constitution
соответствует конститу
Why do
Почему
bailiffs take away property from the Constitution?
Конституции приставы отнимают имущество
If a person cannot pay a fine,
Если человек не может выплатить штраф
this has always been the case in any country, once
это всегда было в любой стране ещё
again the question is not about the
раз вопрос же не о
fine, fines and so look what you did
штрафе штрафы и так смотри вы сделали
there, what kind of fakes are the army? Yes, for example,
там что за фейки армии Да например
some kind of Fine Yes  Well, this already exists
какой-то Штраф Да Ну так это же уже есть
if a person does not
если человек не
pay, they want to make a sanction
выплатит хотят сделать санкцию
confiscation of
конфискацию
property conto is which
имущества конто есть который
implies a fine. I think it will be fine,
подразумевает штраф Я думаю отм будет
but I understand correctly what you
только я правильно понимаю что ты
consider constitutional Yes, deprivation of
считаешь конституционным Да лишение
property of citizens for their personal
имущества граждан за ихнюю личную
position if they cannot pay a fine
позицию если не может выплатить штраф
specifically stop stop stop not  in the fine not
конкретно стоп стоп стоп не в штрафе не
in the piece Igor not in the fine the question You
в шт Игорь не в штрафе вопрос Ты же
understand there is not in the fine there is a direct
понимаешь там не в штрафе там прямо
sanction, it doesn’t say no payment of the
санкцию там же не сказано не выплата
fine it says
штрафа там сказано
that deprivation is
что лишение
more precisely confiscation Yes of property Yes for
точнее конфискация Да имущества Да за
fakes about the
фейки об
army there is nothing about a fine
армии там про штраф ничего не
specifically the law on fines  there is already a
идёт конкретно закон о штрафах уже есть
fine, yes, look, there is no such law on
да штраф Ну смотри нет такого закона о
fines, there is no such law on
штрафах нет такого закона о
fines, but this law does not
штрафах Но этим законом не
provide for any actions
предусмотрено какие-то действия в случае
if a person does not have the money to pay
если у человека нету денег оплатить
the fine again, again no. No
штраф ещё раз ещё раз нет Никаким
law regulates what to do
законом не регламентируется Что делать
if a person does not pay the fine  there is a
если человек не оплатит штраф есть
separate regulation Yes, the resolution is
отдельно регулируется Да постановление
these bailiffs you said, yes, what are they
вот эти приставы ты говорил да как они у
called? Yes, those who collect
вас называются Да которые стягивают
charges according to yours Yes, if a
взимают по вашему взимают Да если
person does not pay his debts, there is not
человек не оплачивает свои долги не
necessarily a fine, so that’s the question. You
обязательно штраф так вот вопрос Ты же
understand. You are a lawyer by training, as I
понимаешь Ты кто по образованию я так
understand it.
понимаю
Yes 4 Federal  look at the law, if
юрист Да 4 Федеральный закон смотри если
you are a lawyer, then you understand
ты вс-таки юрист да то ты понимаешь
the difference between an unpaid traffic ticket. They
разницу между неоплаченным трафо Они и
already have it all, it’s all regulated
так уже есть это всё регламентировано
as a person with an unpaid fine, which is
как человек с неоплаченный штраф что
Cherry juice super Look, you
Вишнёвый сок супер Смотри ты же
understand Agree that there is a mechanism
понимаешь Согласись что есть механизм
for collecting unpaid fines from people,
как взимать с людей неоплаченные штрафы
it already exists
он уже есть
the truth Well, yes, everything is there. That is, don’t
правда Ну да есть всё То есть ты не
fantasize, you won’t take me for a
фантазируй ты меня на лоха не возьмёшь
sucker, it’s like, in short, if a person
что типа это короче если человек не
cannot pay a fine, that is,
может выплатить штраф то есть
confiscation of property - this is not about an
конфискация имущества - это не про не
unpaid fine, they will separately come up with a
выплаченный штраф это отдельно придумают
new sanction for fakes about the army,
новую санкцию за фейки об армии
correctly, Article
правильно статья
the Russian Federation  confiscation of property
УКРФ конфискация имущества
now storage transportation or sale of
сейчас хранение перевозка или сбыт
counterfeit money papers blah blah blah blah
поддельных денег бумаг бла-бла-бла
blah blah blah Let's
блаблабла блаблабла Давайте почитаем
just read this article
просто эту статью
Why do I want to read there I
Зачем мне хочет там
just want to understand they just take away
просто хочу понять просто отнимают
the property without money or take away the
имущество без денег либо отнимают
money first If a person cannot
Сначала деньги Если человек не может
pay the fee you are a lawyer You are a lawyer You
уплатить шра ты юрист Ты юрист Ты
you understand that such property is
понимаешь что такое имущество в
included in the property and money is also maino In
имущество входит и деньги тоже майно У
Ukrainian we call confiscation
нас по-украински называется конфискация
Maina maino property in property is not
Майна майно имущество в имущество это не
only a car, money -
только автомобиль денежные средства -
this is also property you have correctly If
это тоже имущество у вас правильно Если
I'm not
я не
mistaken
ошибаюсь
dadada
дадада
listening so bbb The State Duma adopted a law on
слуша так ббб Госдума приняла закон о
confiscation of
конфискации
property  for fakes again this article,
имущество за фейки опять эту статью вы
did you support him 37 deputies from 4 seats
ли его поддержали 37 депутатов из 4 мест
France New people the document proposes ism
Франция Новые люди документ предлагает
several articles of the Criminal Code,
изма несколько статей
this is again article 104, this is just
укп это опять 104 статья это просто
confiscation of property, this is just a
конфискация имущества это просто
reworking of this
переделка этой
article Well, what is this, well,
статьи Ну
just article 104 of the Criminal Code has been expanded, so it
что ну просто 104 статью УК расширили
has been expanded, yes  that is, having included in it, uh,
вот расширили да то есть внеся в неё ээ
that it can be confiscated because of the fake
что конфисковать можно изза фейки
army Well, yes, that is, no, yes, that is, look, we
армии Ну да то есть не да то есть смотри
are not talking about any unpaid fines.
ни про какие неоплаченные штрафы не идёт
You understand that this is completely
речь Ты же понимаешь что это совсем
different.
другое
Well, here, every lawyer already understands his own
Ну тут уже понимаете каждый юрист своей
version, everything is clear here  don’t look at
какой-то верси тут всё чётко не смотри
everything here clearly, it’s a criminal
тут всё чётко это ж криминальный
criminal code Yes, it’s criminal according to
криминальный кодекс Да уголовный по
you Yes, everything is just clearly
вашему Да там всё как раз чётко
demarcated there, everything is very
разграничена там всё очень
clearly so after all, look, people
чётко так всё-таки да смотри людям
who don’t understand the law Yes, it’s easier to
которые не понимают праве Да легче Лапшу
hang noodles on your ears yes But it won’t work for me,
вешать на уши да А меня не получится
yes it won’t  what does it have to do with
да тут не причём тут
noodles fines there fines
лапша штрафы там штрафы
Yes in any law You need to understand If
Да в любом законе Надо разбираться Если
you are a lawyer You
вы юрист Вы
know yes yes let's
знаете да да
code of the Russian Federation the
давайте кодекс Российской Федерации
main process of the code of the Russian
главный процесс кодекса Российской
Federation with an additional paragraph d
Федерации дополнительным пунктом д
allowing the courts to apply confiscation of
позволяющим судам применять конфискацию
vehicles belonging to the
транспортных средств принадлежащих
accused for the execution of crimes committed under the
обвиняемому исполнению совершенных при
article
статьёй
in this way the person brought to
таким образом лицо привлекаемое к
criminal responsibility  may be deprived of the right to
уголовной ответст может быть лише право
own a vehicle in the case of
владения транспортным средством в случае
driving it while intoxicated b
управление таковым состояни опьянения б
Why are you
Зачем ты это
reading this? I’m reading the article as I’m expanding it,
Читаешь Я читаю статью как её расширяю
why? Yes, so you
зачем Да так ты Прочитай то что
Read what relates to the mob fairies Why read that
относится к фей моба Зачем читать что
confiscation of a vehicle in
конфискация транспортного средства в
drunk driving type Vozh is a flock of koyu
пьяном вождении типа вож это есть стая
just tell me this is what it
просто скажи вот это что
adds. Well, it’s just added in the
дописывает Так ну там просто дописано в
articles for fakes about the army and now I’m
статьях за фейки об армии и всё сейчас
trying to figure it out, but again, you
пытаюсь разобраться но опять же Сами
understand it’s taking a very long time. Why is it taking so
понимаете это очень долго Почему
long to open the adopted law in the first
долго открываешь принятый закон в первом
reading? Well, look at the draft law
чтении Ну и посмотришь проект закона
that was
который
adopted; the bill was
принят
again adopted by the State Duma  the second
опять статья Госдума приняла втором
reading of the confiscation bill is already the
чтени законопроект конфискации уже
second reading
второе чтение
[laughter]
[смех]
was in January the State Duma meeting adopted in the
было января Госдума заседании приняла во
second reading a law that proposes to
втором чтении законо кото предлагается
introduce the Criminal Code of the Russian Federation for possibly
внести Уголовный кодекс РФ возможно
property for fakes of the Russian army and
имущества за фейки российской армии и
public calls for carrying out
публичные призывы к осуществлению
activities aimed against the
деятельности направленной против
security of the state domain Yan Group
безопасности государст домен Ян Груп
Deputy
депу во
headed by Damn text again  no
главе Блин опять текста нету
read here, for example, look here,
чтени вот у нас например смотри у нас
for example, on the website of the Verkhovna Rada Yes, all
например на сайте Верховной Рады Да все
projects, all bills and all laws
проекты все законопроекты и все законы
adopted, as it were, are published
принятые как бы есть публикуются можно
once and can be found, that is, a lawyer. You’ve probably
раз и найти то есть юрист Ты же наверное
looked for bills more than once. Yes, as well as the
не раз искал законопроекты Да как и
stage of their adoption. It can be seen there when
стадия ихнего принятия Видно там когда
voted who
голосовали кто
voted I’m basically surfing the MIS, the
голосовал Я в основном лазию по ИСУ
unified information system is for
единая информационная система это по
government procurement And so,
госзакупкам А так
let’s go to the Constitution of property for
Давайте Конституция имущества за
fakes,
фейки
the text of the
текст
bill and Again, what kind of property did the
законопроекта а Опять какое имущество
bill make changes?
законопроект внесли изменения Да
Yes, my Federation Council committee supported the bill
ё-моё комитет СФ поддержал законопроект
Damn again, I can’t find the text,
Да блин опять Вот я не могу найти текст
seriously  I’m trying to find on each
вот серьёзно я пытаюсь найти на каждой
and I can’t find this text, what’s most
и не могу найти этот текст что самое
surprising is the same
удивительное это та же самая
article: money day money values
статья денежные день деньги ценности
weapons
орудия
I see everywhere only these four
я везде вижу только вот эти вот четыре
articles that contribute And
статьи которые вносят И
here I don’t see anything for the army for some reason
тут я не вижу ничего за армию почему-то
This is
Вот это
strange about
странно об
army, look
армии смотри
Yeah, well, look there
Ага ну ну смотри там
Come on, you, you so boldly started something about
Давай ты ж ты ты так дерзко начинал
some Ukrainian who
что-то про какого-то украинца который
said something to you, I see that you yourself
тебе что-то сказал я смотрю что ты сам в
haven’t seen it in your eyes, yes. The point is that
глаза не видел это да Суть в том-то что
he told me that  the law has already been adopted, I
он мне утверждал что закон уже принят я
told him that this is just a bill,
ему говорил что это только законопроект
I understood, I didn’t claim that it doesn’t
понял я не утверждал что его нету он
exist, it exists, it was adopted in the second reading, I don’t deny
есть он принят уже во втором чтении я
this in any way, I’m
этого не отрицаю ни в коем случае я
trying to find out exactly what was changed, but for some
пытаюсь найти Конкретно что изменили но
reason I can’t specifically
я почему-то не могу именно конкретно
implement it publicly  false
публичное исполнение зано ложной
Information a Consultant plus about the
Информации а Консультант плюс об
execution of the Armed Forces of the Russian
исполнении Вооружённых Сил Российской
Federation the execution of the state
Федерации исполнения государственного
Organ of the Russian Federation of its powers
Орга россий Федерации своих полномочий
voluntary formation of an organization for persons to
доброволь формирования организации лицам
perform tasks blah blah public
выполнения задач бла-бла публичное
dissemination Let me help you,
распространение Давай я тебе помогу
look if I sent you a link to the
смотри если я тебе вот скинул ссылку на
State Duma website, here I sent you a link
сайт Госдумы вот я тебе скинул ссылочку
to
на
site you tell me from the phone it will be the
сайт вы мне я с телефона это будет
State Duma Damn, well, I’ll be rewriting this for a long time,
Госдума Блин ну это я буду долго
I’ll just like this, let’s keep
переписывать я вот так давайте сохраню
you a public face I think you can see me,
вы лицо публичное Я думаю вы меня видите
look, look, I came in, I entered
смот вот смотри я зашёл вот я ввёл тоже
the text too Yes And there’s the State Duma and the army, that’s it
текст Да И вот есть там Госдума й арми
and the link  for this bill directly
всё и ссылка на этот законопроект прямо
to the website of your State Duma Well, that is, if
на сайт вашей Госдумы Ну то есть если
someone from Ukraine found it in a few minutes,
яче из Украины за какие-то минуты Это
but you a lawyer from Russia can’t
нашёл а вы юрист из России не можете
find it. And what article specifically is
найти А какая там статья конкретно
written there? If you opened the link, what article is written there?
там стати написана
104 Open, let me wait.
104 Откройте давайте я подожду Я
look, if I open the link, I’ll slash And so it
смотрите если ссылку открою я слеш А так
will take me a long time to rewrite it. I’m talking about
я долго буду её переписывать Я про
Rewrite Let me dictate to you letter
Перепишите Давайте я вам буду диктовать
by letter there is no link to Article 104 of the Criminal Code of the Russian Federation, they
по буквам нет ссылки на 104 статью УКРФ
are exactly what they have made changes, let’s
идут именно то что внесли изменения
open it now. I don’t mind, I’m just for
откроете Я же не против я только за
understanding Yes  yes Let's
разбираться Да да Давайте
figure it out, the
разберёмся система
support system is like this Federal law
обеспечения так Федеральный закон
conditions general [ __ ] Well here it is
условия общее [__] А ну вот он
Yes PDF file found the State Duma website Yes let's open
Да ПДФ най файл нашёл сайт Госдумы Да
open
открывай открываем
it 11 Dear Article 104 of the Constitution of the
вого 11 Уважаемые статья 104 Конституции
Russian Federation the text of the bill is on the first sheet
РФ текст законопроекта на Первом листе
On the second sheet Federal Law 104 is
На втором листе Федеральный закон 104 то
what I read I  I’m just trying
что я и читал Я просто пытаюсь в нём
to find 2 things in it that I read there
найти 2 вго что что там прочитал
date date
дата дата
1822 This was something a year and a half ago, it
1822 Это что-то было полтора года назад
seems to me Well, this is
кажется Ну это как раз-таки
exactly the changes to the article
это как раз-таки изменения в в статью
changes to Article 104 of the Criminal
изменения в статью 104 Уголовного
Code of the Russian Federation this is it
кодекса Российской Федерации это оно и
this is the twenty-second year this is the second
это дцать второй год это д второ уже
year and a half have already passed, we’re probably
прошло полтора года мы наверное про
talking about something fresh, it’s
нечто свежее говорим
true Federal law blah-blah-blah blah-
правда Федеральный закон бла-бла-бла
blah-blah Now one second Maybe
бла-бла-бла Сейчас одну секунду Может
Okay let’s do it this way you
Ладно давай делаем таким образом ты
get homework to familiarize yourself
получаешь домашнее задание ознакомиться
with this Punisher legislation yes you
с этим Каратель законодательством да
write  the abstract can not be written by hand Yes, you can
пишешь реферат можно не от руки Да можно
write it in the vorka Yes, wait wait
в ворке написать Да ре подожди подожди
wait wait the abstract wait the abstract on whether
подожди реферат подожди реферат о том
these changes comply with the
соответствуют ли эти изменения
Constitution yes And you will send it next
Конституции да И пришлёшь в следующий
time we will meet you will show me I will check your
раз встретимся покажешь я проверю твой
abstract Come on no politely dumbfounded
реферат Давай нет важливо оголошення
write to Tsei reserve channel Andriy
пишиться на Цей резервный канал Андрий
Popik chatroulette me  having created another channel
Попик чатрулетка я створив ще один канал
on a treasure trove of unique videos I didn’t Buli
на який клада уникальни видео Я не Були
on tsmu Kana on streams to sign
на цму Кана на стримах пишиться на нього
up for a new day there every day will be released but and but video
там кожен день будуть виходи но и но
squeak comment PD every video to
вдео писка комент ПД кожним вдео щоб
YouTube yogo effektivni enlighten mi pon
YouTube його ефективни просв ми пон
collapse that channel in order to
рухну той канал для того щоб бильше
remove more people  information from our videos
людей отримували информацию з наших вдео
to what Tsey Our channel Yes, a little bit of YouTube,
тому що Цей Наш канал Да трошки YouTube
having driven the new ban mi, we will try more in
загнав ньй бан ми будем пробу ще
parallel, work one
паралельно робити один
letter
пись
and
а